Preferred Spike Lee joint. Crooklyn or bamboozled? Malcolm X.
So I have to stand here today as what I was when I was born. A black man.
I think that if white people find themselves the victims of the same kind of violence that black people have found themselves victims of here in America,
and if the government was either unable or unwilling to do anything about it, I think that it would be intelligence on their part to defend themselves.
Father only means that you're taking care of your children. That's what it is to be a father.
Father doesn't mean that you're having some babies. Anybody can have a baby.
Having a baby does not make you a father. Anybody can go out and get a woman, but not anybody can take care of that woman.
It's called responsibility.
You're an African who happens to be in America. You have to understand the difference.
We didn't come over on the Nita, the Pinta, and the whatchamacallit. We didn't land on Plymouth Rock. Plymouth Rock landed on us.
For the white man to ask the black man why he hates him is like the wolf asking the sheep or the rapist asking the rape,
do you hate me? The white man is in no moral position to accuse the black man of anything.
There's been times that I could live.
I could live.
There's been times when I couldn't live.